星球大战: 克隆人战争
第5季 第12集 战地失踪
Missing in Action
战士最强大的武器是勇气
山穷水尽!
Stranded!
在为共和国执行一项秘密任务时
On a secret mission for the Republic,
加斯孔上校及其英勇的机器人小队
Colonel Gascon and his intrepid droid squad
成功地从一艘分离势力军舰上
successfully steal an encryption module
窃取了一个加密模块
from a Separatist ship.
在撤离途中, 英雄们迫降在
During their escape, our heroes crash
外环星域的阿巴法星球上
on the Outer Rim planet of Abafar
随即被困在了
and find themselves stranded
一片堪称"虚无"的奇怪荒漠中
in the strange wasteland called The Void.
如今, 在屡次死里逃生后
Now, after surviving against all odds,
英雄们必须设法归航
our heroes must find a way home
并带回加密模块
and deliver the encryption module
以破译分离势力的密码
to crack the Separatist code
并阻止敌人的进攻
and stop an enemy attack.
我从没去过塔图因
I have never been to Tatooine,
但如果这地方让你想起了它, R2
but if this place reminds you of it, Artoo,
就提醒我永远不要去那儿
remind me never to go there.
别瞎想了, QT
Don't be absurd, Qutee.
这些人没有危险性
These people aren't dangerous.
他们中的大多数可能在躲避
Most of these people are probably hiding
什么人或什么事
from someone or something.
这就是在外环星域肮脏角落的生存之道
That's the way it is on these Outer Rim armpits.
没人会自愿来这儿
Nobody's here by choice,
而我更是加倍如此
which goes double for me.
我希望你有个计划
I hope you have a plan
能让我们离开这个角落, 上校
to get us off this armpit, Colonel.
我当然有, 下士
Of course I do, Corporal.
我们只需一条上行通信链路
All we need is a communications uplink
以及一些燃料
and some fuel.
谢谢提醒, C4
Thank you for the reminder, Ceefor,
可我很清楚我们的穿梭机坠毁在"虚无"之地了
but I'm well aware our shuttle's lost in The Void.
我是在说给我自己的燃料
I'm talking about fuel for me.
你们机器人可以靠电池能量混日子
You droids can putter along on battery power
可我需要食物才能活下去
but I need food to survive.
我的电池能量也快用完了
My power cells are running low too,
要是能来次油浴就爽了
and an oil bath would be nice.
这些尘土一直折磨着我的关节
All this dust is wreaking havoc on my joints.
算了吧, BZ
Forget it, Beezee.
我们不是来这儿度假的
We're not on vacation here.
R2, 加密模块还安全吗?
Artoo, is the encryption module safe?
除了死亡和肢解
Nothing short of death or dismemberment
没什么能阻止米布尔・加斯孔上校
will stop Colonel Meebur Gascon
把那个模块带回科洛桑
from delivering that module to Coruscant.
嗯, 我会的
Well, I'll be.
餐馆. 吃饭的地方
A diner. A place of eating.
哈, 我得救了
[chuckles] I'm saved.
R2, 你和其他技工侦察一下四周
Artoo, you and the other 'mechs scout the perimeter.
看看附近有没有不友好的事物
Find out if there are any unfriendlies around.
下士
Corporal,
你和我去这个美食餐馆里补充燃料
you and I will refuel in this fine establishment.
日安
Good day.
我是大共和国军的加斯孔上校
I am Colonel Gascon of the Grand Army of the Republic.
我来这儿执行非常重要的任务
And I am here on very important business.
我时间紧迫
I don't have much time,
所以请你热情待客, 给我端上今天的特价菜
so if you'll be so kind as to fix me your daily special
并为我的机器人充电
and let my droid recharge.
不招待机器人
No droids.
好吧
Fine.
在外面等我, 下士
Wait for me outside, Corporal.
我们也不招待你这类的
We don't serve your type either.
你指的是哪一类?
What type are you referring to?
电线虫
Conduit worms.
求你看看清楚. 我是个齐尔金人
I beg your pardon. I am a Zilkin.
你会求我饶命
You'll be begging for your life
如果你不快滚的话
if you don't beat it.
快滚
Beat it.
啊-哦
Uh-oh.
啊!
Ah!
这是迫害!
This is an outrage!
那个怪物将来会后悔
That monstrosity will rue the day
今天不允许我吃饭的
he denied me a meal.
我不是火上浇油, 上校
I would not push it, Colonel.
那个怪物会把你做成饭的
That monstrosity might make a meal out of you.
唉. 我不在乎
[sighs] I don't care.
我饿死了
I'm famished.
我想我可以帮你
I think I can help.
你的饭准备好了, 长官
Your meal awaits you, sir.
你这个短路的液压扳手
You short-circuiting hydrospanner,
那不是饭
that's no meal.
那是垃圾
That is garbage.
有什么区别吗?
What is the difference?
这是可以吃的, 不是吗?
It is edible, is it not?
呃
[sighs]
啊! 咳!
Agh! [coughs]
啊, 哦, 对不起
Oh, uh, I'm sorry.
我没看见你在那儿
I didn't see you there.
听着, 我可以给你拿些食物
Look, I could get you some food,
但通常人们都从前门进来
but normally people come in the front door.
不过没问题
But there's no problem.
你知道你是在吃垃圾, 对吧?
You do know that you're eating garbage, right?
你是个克隆人
You're a clone.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
啊, 我--
Uh, I--
我不知道
I wouldn't know about that.
我--我叫格雷戈尔
My--my name's Gregor.
等等, 克隆人是什么?
Uh, wait, what's a clone?
你是个克隆人
You are a clone.
你是在执行卧底任务吗?
Are you working undercover?
我不懂你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
听我说, 士兵
Listen to me, soldier,
不管你的任务是什么
whatever your assignment is,
都不会比我的更重要
it can't be more important than mine.
这是他的第一次实际任务
It is his first real mission.
他只是个地图研究员
He is just a map reader.
别听那蠢货的
Don't listen to that ignoramus.
你是个克隆人, 共和国军队的士兵
You are a clone and a soldier in the Republic Army,
我命令你带我去你的飞船
and I order you to take me to your ship.
我们需要立即返回科洛桑
We need to get back to Coruscant immediately.
听着, 朋友, 我只是想帮个忙
Uh, look, friend, I was just trying to help.
很抱歉让你产生了误解
I'm sorry if you took it the wrong way.
我觉得那个士兵不相信你是位上校
I do not think that soldier believes you are a colonel,
啊, 上校
uh, Colonel.
格雷戈尔!
Gregor!
回来干活!
Get back to work!
啊, 请原谅. 我得走了
Uh, excuse me. I got to go.
我不想丢掉工作
I don't want to lose my job.
可我还饿着呢
But I'm still hungry.
那么, 侦察报告是什么情况?
Well, what's the scouting report?
分离势力机器人?
Separatist droids?
嗯, 那么, 事情变复杂了
Hmm, well, that complicates matters.
那个, 啊, 老板
So, uh, boss,
您知道, 我只是想...
you know, I was just wondering...
不, 你不会有加薪的, 格雷戈尔
No, you can't have a raise, Gregor.
哦, 不, 不, 不, 不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
我不是要加薪, 先生
I don't want a raise, sir.
我-我只是想知道, 克隆人是什么?
I-I just wanted to know, what's a clone?
今天有人告诉我说我是个克隆人
Someone told me I was a clone today.
他们一口咬定
They insisted.
呵. 克隆人?
Heh. A clone?
克隆人在银河系各地打仗
Clones fight battles across the galaxy.
他们是勇敢的战士
They are brave soldiers.
那听起来像你吗?
Does that sound like you?
你是个洗碗工, 格雷戈尔
You're a dishwasher, Gregor.
别再想克隆人或类似的任何事
Forget about clones or anything like that.
你在这儿拥有很好的生活
You have good life here,
简单的生活
a simple life.
比博尔库斯发现你时的生活要好得多
More than you had when Borkus found you.
我-我知道, 先生
I-I know, sir.
我很感激您所做的一切. 相信我
And I appreciate everything that you've done. Believe me.
可我想也许您可以--
But I thought maybe you could--
可以告诉我, 我是怎么到这儿来的?
could you tell me, how did I get here?
您在哪儿发现我的?
Where did you find me?
别问了. 回家, 睡觉吧
Enough questions. Go home. Sleep.
明天再来. 干你的活
Come back tomorrow. Do your job.
而且我不想再听到"克隆人"这个词
And I don't ever want to hear that word "clone" again,
明白吗?
understand?
上校, 我不由得注意到
Colonel, I cannot help noticing
我们已经在实行第三套计划了
that we are already on our third plan.
聪明的战略需要
Smart battle strategy requires
灵活机动和随机应变
flexibility and improvisation,
而这是机器人所不具备的
something droids are not known for.
R2说的对
Artoo is right.
机器人之所以不知变通
Droids are not known for being flexible,
是因为程序让我们从一开始就正确行事
because we are programmed to be right the first time.
好吧, 回答我, 下士
Well, answer me this, Corporal,
如果绝地委员会认为你们机器人中的某一个
if the Jedi Council thought one of you droids
能更好地领导这次任务
were better prepared to lead this mission,
那他们为什么让我来指挥?
then why did they put me in charge?
因为你是唯一一个能装进BZ的人
'Cause you were the only one who could fit inside Beezee.
不, 是因为我的推理能力告诉我
No, it is because my power of deduction told me
如果阿巴法上有分离势力机器人
that if there are Separatist droids on Abafar,
那么附近一定有停机坪
then there must be a landing zone nearby
而那儿无疑会有一架能带我们回家的穿梭机
where there will be no doubt a shuttle to take us home.
下士, 这才是由我指挥的原因
That, Corporal, is why I am in charge.
现在, 我们要潜行到那儿, 神不知鬼不觉地
Now, we are going to waltz down there, undetected,
就像我们在无畏舰上干过的一样
just like we did on the dreadnought,
然后兵不血刃地征用那架穿梭机
and commandeer that shuttle without incident.
技工们说的有道理, 上校
The 'mechs have a point, Colonel.
我们在无畏舰上大闹一通之后
After what we did on the dreadnought,
那些战斗机器人恐怕已经有了我们的身份扫描记录
those battle droids probably have our identities scanned.
这回我们不得不杀出一条通往穿梭机的路了
We will have to fight our way onto the shuttle this time.
嗯, 你们机器人可能说的有道理
Hmm, you droids may have a point.
但就算发配我去马拉科
But there's no way in Malachor
我也不会率领这支可怜的小队
that I'm going to lead this pitiful squad
对停机坪发动袭击
on an assault of that landing zone.
现在有什么计划, 上校?
What is the plan now, Colonel?
我们要等到我们的克隆人下班
We're going to wait until our clone gets off work,
然后征召他入伙, 不管他愿不愿意
then enlist his help, whether he wants to or not.
雷克斯上尉奉命报到
Captain Rex reporting for duty.
啊! 什么?
Agh! What?
我...
I...
我不明白
I don't understand.
那是我吗?
That's me?
不, 那是雷克斯上尉
No, that's Captain Rex.
他是共和国军队中的一名克隆人
He's a clone in the Republic Army,
就像你一样, 格雷戈尔
just like you, Gregor.
我无法相信
I can't believe it.
好吧, 慢点来, 慢点来
Okay, slow down. Slow down.
你的意思是说
So you're telling me that
还有更多这样的克隆人?
there are more of these clones?
有数百万之众. 整整一支军队
Millions. A whole army's worth.
啊-哈
Uh-huh.
而且他们都和我一模一样?
And they all look exactly like me?
不, 那些克隆人是战士
No, those clones are warriors,
是共和国培育的职业军人
professional soldiers created by the Republic,
被训练来打仗, 且不怕牺牲
trained to fight, and die if necessary,
为打倒分离势力而战斗
in our war against the Separatists.
他们不是洗碗工
They're not dishwashers
住在害虫窝里的洗碗工
living in some vermin-infested hovel.
听着, 能住在这儿我很幸运
Look, I'm lucky to live in this place.
博尔库斯先生说我的工资还不够付租金的
Mr. Borkus says my salary doesn't even cover the rent,
所以他帮我垫了差价
so he pays the difference for me.
你还不明白吗, 格雷戈尔?
Don't you get it, Gregor?
你是他的奴隶
You're his slave.
我们得搞清楚你到底是谁
We need to figure out who you really are,
你怎么来这儿的
how you got here.
你真的什么也不记得了吗?
Are you sure you don't remember anything?
嗯, 我只记得
Well, all I remember is
在一架运输机上醒过来
waking up on a transport.
我们不知怎么地坠毁在了阿巴法
Somehow we crashed on Abafar.
然后, 嗯, 博尔库斯先生说
And, well, Mr. Borkus says
我失忆了
I have amnesia.
嗯
Hmm.
每个克隆人的手腕上都有识别码
Every clone has an identifying code on their wrist.
你的军事履历就记录在数据库里
Your military records will be in the database.
扫描他, R2
Scan him, Artoo.
厉害
Impressive.
格雷戈尔, 你的编号是CC-5576-39
Gregor, your designation is CC-5576-39.
你是一名上尉, 隶属于一支精英小队
You were a captain and part of an elite squad.
克隆人突击队
A clone commando.
你的档案表明
Your file says you were reported
你在萨里什战役中
missing in action during
被报告为战斗失踪人员
the Battle of Sarrish.
萨里什?
Sarrish?
萨里什
Sarrish.
等等
Wait.
什么是萨里什战役?
What was the Battle of Sarrish?
那是共和国最惨痛的失利之一
It was one of the Republic's most devastating losses.
萨里什
Sarrish.
没错
Yes.
没错, 我现在记起来了
Yes, I remember now.
那么多的士兵都死掉了
So many soldiers were dying.
你还记得你是怎么逃离萨里什的吗?
Do--do you remember how you escaped Sarrish?
不
No.
我只记得看见那些尸体
I just remember seeing all those bodies.
尸横遍野
Bodies everywhere.
我知道我必须寻求救助
I knew I had to get help.
但记忆到这儿就中断了
But that's where the memory stops.
好吧, 士兵
Well, soldier,
现在你没法再为那场战役做什么了
there's nothing you can do about that battle now,
可你能帮助我们
but you can help us.
我们的任务就指望你了
Our mission depends on it.
啊, 上校
Uh, Colonel,
格雷戈尔说给他五分钟
Gregor said to give him five minutes,
但已经过去六分钟了
but it has been six.
如果他拒绝加入我们, 该怎么办?
What if he does not accept your offer to join us?
那我会回到里面去
Then I'll go back in there
然后亲自给他开开窍
and personally knock some sense into him.
没那个必要了
That won't be necessary.
哇哦!
Whoa!
我觉得在找回我的装备前
I figured at least looking like a soldier
至少让自己看起来像个士兵
might bring back some more memories,
可能有助于拾回一些记忆
until we recover my equipment anyway.
我碰巧听见了你们的对话
I overheard you guys talking.
我想我知道我的盔甲在哪儿
I think I know where my armor is.
我们回餐馆找找
Let's go check out the diner.
加快速度, 士兵们. 这可不是在开派对
Step it up, soldiers. This isn't a party.
我们没有一整晚的时间
We do not have all night.
在找这个吗?
Looking for this?
我的军服. 我的装备
My uniform. My equipment.
你一直都知道我是谁, 却不告诉我
All this time you knew who I was and didn't tell me.
为什么?
Why?
我不在乎你过去是谁
I don't care who you were.
你现在就是个洗碗工
You are dishwasher now.
是我在你坠机时救了你, 你欠我的
And you owe me for saving you from your crash.
你的命是我的, 格雷戈尔
Your life is mine, Gregor.
你没有救我
You didn't save me.
你把我变成了奴隶
You turned me into a slave.
我听从你的命令, 在这个垃圾场干活
I've worked in this dump taking orders from you
而我本该为共和国而战
when I could have been fighting for the Republic.
我要回到我的生活
I want my life back.
你想要自由吗, 格雷戈尔?
You want your freedom, Gregor?
从我手里夺回你的枪啊
Take your gun from me.
让我看看你的战士本色
Show me you are a soldier.
看见了吗?
You see?
你不是战士
You are no soldier.
你就是个洗碗工
You are a dishwasher.
哈哈哈哈!
[laughing]
干什么, 你们这些坏机器人
Why, you no-good droids.
放开我!
Let go of me!
啊! 哦
Agh! Oh.
拿上你的东西, 格雷戈尔
Take your things, Gregor.
我们离开这儿
We're getting out of here.
别走, 格雷戈尔
Don't leave, Gregor.
外面的银河系纷繁复杂
It's a big galaxy out there,
远远超出你的认知
bigger than you know.
留在这儿, 过简单的生活
Stay here, where your life is simple.
简单不再等同美好了
Simple isn't good enough anymore.
我这个克隆人不满足于此
Not for this clone.
哈! 你永远都不可能离开阿巴法
Ha! You will never get off Abafar,
你和你的共和国小朋友们
you and your little Republic friends,
只能看着你们的绝地巡洋舰被炸飞
not after your Jedi cruiser blows up.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
你以为分离势力不辞辛苦来这儿是为了什么?
Why do you think the Separatists bother coming here?
他们正在开采我们的赖登素
They are mining our Rhydonium
用穿梭机满载着去摧毁来接你们回家的那艘船
to load on the shuttle and destroy your ride home.
你们看着吧
You will see.
你们都会被困在这儿
You will all be stuck here
在博尔库斯的餐馆里乞求一份工作
begging Borkus for a job in his diner.
哈哈哈哈!
[laughing]
好吧, 我们来看看面对的是什么
Okay, let's see what we're up against.
格雷戈尔
Gregor.
等等. 那儿
Wait. There.
天上有一艘巡洋舰
There's a cruiser up there.
至于那架穿梭机, 我想--
And that shuttle, I think--
没错, 它正在装载赖登素储存罐
Yes, it's being loaded up with Rhydonium canisters.
嘿. 我猜博尔库斯先生
Huh. I guess Mr. Borkus
总算是说了一回实话
was actually telling the truth...for once.
赖登素到底是什么?
What exactly is Rhydonium?
它是一种燃料
It's a fuel.
大部分开采自阿巴法
Mostly been mined out on Abafar.
易爆炸很危险
It's volatile and dangerous.
好吧, 我们确实有了个新任务:
Yes, we do have a new mission:
阻止分离势力炸毁那艘巡洋舰
Stop the Separatists from blowing up that cruiser.
我负责开路及掩护你们, 上校
I'll cover you and clear the way, Colonel.
你们全体直奔穿梭机
You all head straight to the shuttle.
我来照顾那些铁皮军
I'll take care of those clankers.
嗯, 听起来是个好计划
Hmm, sounds like a good plan.
你们这些士兵准备好去冒险了吗?
You soldiers ready to get dangerous?
我在穿梭机上与你们会合, 长官
I'll meet you at the shuttle, sir.
大家上吧
Let's roll.
嘿!
Hey!
你们需要授权才能进入本区域
You need authorization to enter this area.
抓住他们!
Get them!
干得好, 格雷戈尔
Good job, Gregor.
看, 他在那上面!
Look, he's up there!
继续前进就好
Just keep moving.
一切尽在掌握
It is all under control.
我开始记起来我有多恨这些家伙了
I'm beginning to remember how much I hate these guys.
嘿, 我不认识那些宇航技工机器人
Hey, I don't recognize those astromechs.
干掉他们!
Blast them!
他们冲我们来了
They are on to us.
上校, 你能听见吗?
Colonel, can you hear me?
先救你们自己吧!
Save yourselves!
好吧. 哇!
Okay. Whoa!
哇-哦-哦
Whoa-oh-oh.
大家都到齐了吗?
Did everybody make it?
还没, BZ和上校仍然困在那儿
No, Beezee and the Colonel are still out there.
让穿梭机准备出发
Get the shuttle ready to roll.
上校, 您还好吗?
Colonel, you all right?
我没可能活着回去了
I'll never make it back alive.
不, 您可以的, 长官
Yes, you will, sir.
这是我生来便被赋予的使命
This is what I was born to do.
现在, 赶紧走别耽搁
Now, go before it's too late.
很荣幸能为您效力, 上校
It's been an honor serving with you, Colonel.
R2是对的
Artoo's right.
我们可以绕回来接你上船
We can swing back around and pick you up.
别担心我
Don't worry about me.
是你们让我记起了我是谁
You made me remember who I am.
我会杀出一条路回家的. 我保证
I'll make my way home. I promise.
快走!
Now go!
格雷戈尔在哪儿?
Where is Gregor?
他在履行士兵的天职:
He's doing what a soldier does:
牺牲自己拯救他人
sacrificing himself for the lives of others.
你将被世人铭记, 格雷戈尔上尉
You will be remembered, Captain Gregor.
我们会把你的英雄事迹带回共和国
We will take your heroic story back to the Republic,
并期待你的归来
and we will watch for your return.
翻译: aweng, 好名想不出, 0de浪漫
校对: DataLore, 雏龙先生
调轴: DataLore
-=星球大战论坛 (www.starwarschina.com)=-
-=伊甸园美剧交流站 (bbs.sfile2012.com)=-
联合荣誉奉献精品字幕!
本字幕仅供爱好者交流, 严禁用于任何商业途径
(译注: 电线虫形似电线, 住在电线管道内,
以吞食电流为生, 故而得名, 是一种害虫.
钻入飞船的电线虫会导致飞船电力中断)
(译注: 曼达洛人战争末期,
质量阴影发生器在马拉科星球启动,
导致那里成为飞船坟场)